Mitchell, John Papers on Microfilm 5502 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
In April, 1907, Mitchell suffered an appendectomy from which he did not fully recover until June. Late that month he traveled west to Montana and Wyoming on UMW business. By October of that year, Mitchell was again in poor health, and as a result, announced that he would not stand for reelection. On March 19, 1908, he stepped down as president before an appreciative convention.
Mitchell accepted employment with the National Civic Federation in August, 1908. Organized in 1900, the Federation sought to study and debate issues affecting United States' foreign and domestic policy, to mobilize enlightened public opinion on these issues, and to secure appropriate legislation relating to the same. While affiliated with this group, Mitchell was chairman of its Trade Agreement Department. In this capacity, he hoped to be able to bring about a better understanding by employers of the aims and methods of trade unionism. While he considered the work worthwhile, he did confide to Samuel Gompers that it was a bit of a letdown after his UMW endeavors. Unfortunately for Mitchell, the National Civic Federation was unpopular with many militant labor leaders because its membership included bitter foes of unionism. The radical element within the UMW continuously sought to persuade Mitchell to resign his position; they succeeded in 1911 when the union passed a resolution that made it a matter of expulsion for any UMW member to belong to the National Civic Federation.
Between 1911 and 1915, Mitchell was involved in the activities of the National Child Labor Committee, the American Academy of Political and Social Science, the American Association for Labor Legislation, New York Peace Society, National Committee on Prison Labor, Travelers' Aid Society, and the National Woman's Trade Union League. Also during this period he undertook extensive public speaking tours for the Lyceum and Chautauqua circuits and under the guidance of his own agent. In June, 1915, he was appointed by Governor Glynn as chairman of the New York State Industrial Commission, a post he held until his death in 1919. As chairman, Mitchell was frequently called on to investigate and arbitrate labor-management disputes. Mitchell's duties in this capacity included the prevention of violations of New York's labor laws and the administration of the Workmen's Compensation Law and the State Insurance Fund.
During World War I, Mitchell carried the additional burden of the chairmanship of the New York State Food Commission. The Commission kept an eye on food production, offering advice on how to increase production and how to save food for the war effort, as well as opposing food price gouging and profiteering. Simultaneously, Mitchell was president of the New York State Council of Farms and Markets, chairman of the Federal Food Board, and chairman of the Federal Milk Commission for the eastern states. His last public appearance was in Syracuse before the New York State Federation of labor in August, 1919.
In early August, 1919, Mitchell presided at a public hearing in the Rome brass and copper strike. After the bitterly contested hearing closed, he set out with friends on a vacation trip, but shortly after the trip began, he experienced a gall stone attack and returned to New York City for surgery. He died on September 9, 1919, following an operation at Post-Graduate Hospital. Funeral services were conducted at the Roman Catholic Cathedral of the Diocese of Scranton, Pennsylvania, at which city his remains were interred.
Scope and Contents
The papers of John Mitchell contain correspondence (1885-1919), reports and proceedings, pamphlets, and photographs primarily in connection with Mitchell's leading role in the coal-mining industry, the labor movement, and in American industrial relations.
Correspondence constitutes the bulk of the collection. It can be divided roughly into three major areas, reflecting Mitchell's affiliations with the United Mine Workers of America, the National Civic Federation, and New York State Commissions. There is much correspondence relating to the affairs of the American Federation of Labor, as well.
Other significant files include minutes of the United Mine Workers National Executive Board (1900-1908), A.F.of L. Executive Council minutes (1902-1913), and those of the New York State Food Commission (1917-1919) the New York State Workman's Compensation Commission (1914-1919) and the New York State Industrial Commission (1914-1919).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4073: James O. Morris Office Files /4256: ILR Press Article Reprints and Promotional Materials 5301/1 mf: UMWA Records: Series 1. Joint Conventions and Conference Proceedings on Microfilm 5360: Buck's Stove and Range Company vs. American Federation of Labor Court Records 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 5616: Isaac Max Rubinow Papers 5780/178: ILGWU Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets 5966: National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor Pamphlets and Leaflets 6034: Rare Pamphlet Collection 6046: Archives Union File (AUF) 6152: New York State Department of Labor Files
Anthracite Coal Strike, Pennsylvania, 1900.; Anthracite Coal Strike, United States, 1902.; Coal-miners.; Industrial relations -- New York (State) -- State supervision.; Labor leaders.; Miners.; Strikes and lockouts -- Coal mining industry -- United States.; Mitchell, John; Turcheneske, John A.; American Federation of Labor; National Civic Federation (U.S.); New York (State) -- Food Commission; New York (State) -- Industrial Commission.; New York (State) -- Workman's Compensation Commission.; United Mine Workers of America.
3337362
- Correspondence. 7/12/1885-6/30/1900 (Reel 1)
- Correspondence. 7/1/1900-6/30/1901 (Reel 2)
- Correspondence. 7/1/1901-1901, n.d. (Reel 3)
- Correspondence. 1/1/1902-10/13/1902 (Reel 4A)
- Correspondence. 1/1/1902-10/13/1902. Copy 2. (Reel 4B)
- Correspondence. 10/14/1902-2/30/03 (Reel 5A)
- Correspondence. 10/14/1902-2/30/03. Copy 2. (Reel 5B)
- Correspondence. 3/1/1903-10/24/1903 (Reel 6)
- Correspondence. 10/26/1903-1/25/1904 (Reel 7)
- Correspondence. 1/26/1904-12/6/1904 (Reel 8)
- Correspondence. 12/7/1904-6/15/1905 (Reel 9)
- Correspondence. 6/16/1905-3/14/1906 (Reel 10)
- Correspondence. 3/15/1906-4/9/1907 (Reel 11)
- Correspondence. 4/10/1907-12/5/1907 (Reel 12)
- Correspondence. 12/6/1907-7/24/1908 (Reel 13)
- Correspondence. 7/25/1908-12/8/1908 (Reel 14)
- Correspondence. 12/9/1908-3/15/1909 (Reel 15)
- Correspondence. 3/16/1909-8/31/1909 (Reel 16)
- Correspondence. 7/1/1909-12/4/1909 (Reel 17)
- Correspondence. 12/5/1909-1909, n.d. (Reel 18)
- Correspondence. 1/1/1910-5/7/1910 (Reel 19)
- Correspondence. 5/9/1910-9/24/1910 (Reel 20)
- Correspondence. 9/26/1910-1910 n.d. (Reel 21)
- Correspondence. 1910, n.d.-3/20/1911 (Reel 22)
- Correspondence. 3/21/1911-7/30/1911 (Reel 23)
- Correspondence. 8/1/1911-12/31/1911 (Reel 24)
- Correspondence. 1911, n.d.-3/11/1912 (Reel 25)
- Correspondence. 3/12/1912-8/9/1912 (Reel 26)
- Correspondence. 9/10/1912-1912, n.d. (Reel 27)
- Correspondence. 1/1/1913-5/5/1913 (Reel 28)
- Correspondence. 5/5/1913-10/30/1913 (Reel 29)
- Correspondence. 11/2/1913-4/11/1914 (Reel 30)
- Correspondence. 4/13/1914-12/17/1914 (Reel 31)
- Correspondence. 12/18/1914-10/15/1915 (Reel 32)
- Correspondence. 10/18/1915-10/30/1916 (Reel 33)
- Correspondence. 11/1/1916-7/30/1917 (Reel 34)
- Correspondence. 8/1/1917-3/4/1918 (Reel 35)
- Correspondence. 3/5/1918-12/17/1918 (Reel 36)
- Correspondence. 12/18/1918-6/19/1919 (Reel 37)
- Correspondence. 6/23/1919-Undated (Reel 38)
- Undated correspondence. (Reel 39)
- Undated correspondence. (Reel 40)
- Minutes, Proceedings, Constitutions and Reports 1891-1908 (Reel 41)
  - Minutes of the National Executive Board, 1900, Feb-1908, Mar, 1900-1908; 1 (Reel 41)
  - Proceedings of the First Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1891; 2 (Reel 41)
    Scope and Contents
    Held at Columbus, Ohio on February 10-17, 1891. Columbus: Myers Bros., 1891. 64 pp
  - Proceedings of the Ninth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1899; 3 (Reel 41)
    Held at Columbus, Ohio, January Eleventh, 1898. Indianapolis: Indiana Newspaper Union, 1898. 32pp.
  - Proceedings of the Tenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1899; 4 (Reel 41)
    Held at Pittsburg, Pennsylvania, January Ninth, 1899. Indianapolis: Indiana Newspaper Union, 1899. 43pp.
  - Proceedings of the Eleventh Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1900; 5 (Reel 41)
    Held at Indianapolis, Indiana, January Fifteenth, Nineteen Hundred. Indianapolis: Indiana Newspaper Union, 1900. 68pp.
  - Proceedings of the Twelfth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1901; 6 (Reel 41)
    Held at Indianapolis, Indiana, January 21 to 30 (Inclusive). Indianapolis: Hollenbeck Press, 1901. 112pp
  - Minutes of the Thirteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1902; 7 (Reel 41)
    Held at Indianapolis, Indiana, January 20 to 29, 1902, Inclusive. Indianapolis: Hollenbeck Press, 1902. 188pp.
  - Minutes of the Fourteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1903; 8 (Reel 41)
    Held in the City of Indianapolis, Indiana, January 19 to 27 Inclusive. Indianapolis: Hollenbeck Press, 1903. 508pp.
  - Minutes of the Fifteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1904; 9 (Reel 41)
    Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1904. 319pp.
  - Minutes of the Sixteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1905; 10 (Reel 41)
    Held in the City of Indianapolis, Indiana, January 16 to 23, 1905 Inclusive. Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1905. 363pp.
  - Minutes of the 17th Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1906; 11 (Reel 41)
    Indianapolis: The Cheltenham Press, 1906. 466pp.
- Minutes, Proceedings, Constitutions and Reports 1891-1908 (Reel 42)
  - Minutes of the Special Convention: United Mine Workers of America, 1906; 1 (Reel 42)
    Held in the German House: Indianapolis, Indiana, March 15-30, 1906. Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1906. 102pp.
  - Proceedings of the Eighteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1907; 2 (Reel 42)
    Held in the City of Indianapolis, Indiana, Jan. 15-22, '07, Inclusive. Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1907. 466pp.
  - Proceedings of the Nineteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1908; 3 (Reel 42)
    Held in the City of Indianapolis, Ind. January 21 to February 3, Inclusive. Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1908. 536p.
  - Proceedings of the Reconvened Nineteenth Annual Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, 1908; 4 (Reel 42)
    Held in the City of Indianapolis, Indiana, March 12th to March 20, Inclusive, 1908. Indianapolis: Cheltenham Press, 1908. 112pp.
  - Constitution and Laws of the United Mine Workers of America, 1890; 5 (Reel 42)
    Np, 1890. (4pp)
  - Constitution and Laws of the United Mine Workers of America, 1896; 6 (Reel 42)
    Established January 25th, 1890, Amended 1896. Columbus: Myers Bros., 1896. 16pp
  - Constitution and Laws of the United Mine Workers of America, 1900; 7 (Reel 42)
    Revision, 1900. Indianapolis: Indiana Newspaper Union, 1900. 16pp
  - Constitution and Laws of the National Union, United Mine Workers of America, 1901; 8 (Reel 42)
    Revision, 1901. Joliet: Republican Printing, 1901. 24pp.
  - "Report of Special convention of the United Mineworkers of America Called to Consider the Strike on the Anthracite Field, Indianapolis, Ind., July 17-19, 1902.", 9 (Reel 42)
    ts. 105pp.
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 1. American Federation of Labor, Minutes of the Executive Committee, Apr 14, 1902-Oct 21-1911. Copy 2. (Reel 43A)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 1. American Federation of Labor, Minutes of the Executive Committee, Apr 14, 1902-Oct 21-1911 (Reel 43B)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 2. American Federation of Labor, President's Reports, 1907-1910; Part 3. American Federation of Labor, Secretary's Reports, 1902-1913- (Reel 44)
  - American Federation of Labor, Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1912; 1 (Reel 44)
    January 8, 1912
  - American Federation of Labor, President's Reports, 1907-1910; 2 (Reel 44)
  - American Federation of Labor, Secretary's Reports, 1902-1913; 3 (Reel 44)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 4. New York State Food Commission, Minutes, 1917-1919; Part 5. New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, 1914-Feb 29, 1916 (Reel 45)
  - New York State Food Commission, Minutes, 1917-1919; 1 (Reel 45)
  - New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, 1914-1916; 2 (Reel 45)
    1914-February 29, 1916
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 5. New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, Mar 2, 1916-Dec 27 1916 (Reel 46)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 5. New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, Jan 3, 1917 - Dec 27, 1917 (Reel 47)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 5. New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, Jan 2, 1918 - Sept 25, 1918 (Reel 48)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 6. New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, May 29, 1914 (Reel 49)
  - New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, 1914; 1 (Reel 49)
    May 29, 1914.
  - New York State Industrial Commission, Administrative Minutes and Index, 1918; 2 (Reel 49)
    October 1, 1918.
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 6. New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, Jun 1, 1914 - Jul 31, 1914 (Reel 50)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 6. New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, Aug 3, 1914 - Sept 21, 1914 (Reel 51)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 6. New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, Oct 1, 1914 - Feb 27, 1915 (Reel 52)
- Miscellaneous Minutes, Proceedings, and Reports. Part 6. New York State Workman's Compensation Commission, Minutes, Mar 1, 1915 - Jul 9, 1919 (Reel 53)
- Printed Matter, 1888-1912 (Reel 54)
  - Adler, Felix. The Ethics of the Labor Struggle., 1 (Reel 54)
    New York: Ethical Record, nd. 30pp
  - Adler, Felix. The Evils Disclosed by the Coal Strike., 1902; 2 (Reel 54)
    New York: Ethical Record, 1902. 24pp.
  - Agreement Between Miners and Operators of the Eighth District of Illinois., 3 (Reel 54)
    Peoria: np, no date. 14pp.
  - Amberg, Emil. The Fraction of Progress., 1903; 4 (Reel 54)
    Detroit: The American Press, 1903. [7pp]
  - Argument of Hon. C.N. Brumm of Council for the United Mine Workers of America., 1903; 5 (Reel 54)
    Philadelphia: Anthracite Coal Strike Commission, 1903. 42pp
  - Argument of H.T. Newcomb of Council for the Philadelphia and Reading Coal and Iron Company., 1903; 6 (Reel 54)
    Philadelphia: Anthracite Coal Strike Commission, 1903. 104pp.
  - Beebe, James C. Common Sense Measures for Protection to Mines and Miners., 1907; 7 (Reel 54)
    No place or publisher, [1907]. 11pp
  - Casson, Herbert N. Common Sense on the Labor Question., 8 (Reel 54)
    New York: Gold sleeve Press, no date. 61pp.
  - Chaplin, Heman. The Coal Mines and the Public., 1902; 9 (Reel 54)
    New York: J.B. Millet Co., 1902. 63pp.
  - Coal Miners' Strike, 1897: Supplement to the Sixteenth Annual Coal Report of the Bureau of Labor Statistics., 10 (Reel 54)
    Springfield: State of Illinois, 1897. 29pp.
  - Compilation of Grievances and Action Thereon., 1903; 11 (Reel 54)
    Scranton: Sanders Printing Co., 1903. 70pp
  - Danryid, Lemuel. History and Philosophy of the Eight Hour Movement, 1899; 12 (Reel 54)
    Washington: Allied Printing, 1899. 15 pp.
  - Fourth Annual Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, and Pennsylvania., 1901; 13 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: Faithorn Printing Co., 1901. 188pp.
  - Gunton, George. The Economic and Social Importance of the Eight Hour Movement., 1889; 14 (Reel 54)
    Washington: Allied Printing, 1889. 24 pp.
  - Gompers, Samuel. The Eight Hour Workday: Its Inauguration, Enforcement, and Influence., 15 (Reel 54)
    Washington: American Federation of Labor, nd. 9pp
  - The Illinois Coal Operators Association: Joint Interstate Agreement, District and Local Agreements for the Year Ending March 31, 1901., 1900; 16 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: Allied Printing, 1900. 30pp
  - The Illinois Coal Operators Association: Joint Interstate Agreement, District and Local Agreements, for the Scale Year Ending March 31, 1902., 1901; 17 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: Allied Printing, 1901. 38pp
  - The Illinois Coal Operators Association: Joint Interstate Agreement, District and Local Agreements for the Scale Year Ending March 31, 1903., 1902; 18 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: Faithorn Printing, 1902. 95pp.
  - Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Western Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana, and Illinois., 1902; 19 (Reel 54)
    Joliet: Allied Printing, 1906. 272pp.
  - Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Western Pennsylvania, Ohio, and Indiana., 1908; 20 (Reel 54)
    Toledo: no publisher, 1908. 275pp.
  - John Mitchell Exposed., 21 (Reel 54)
    New York: Labor News Co., no date. 32pp.
  - Justi, Herman. The Organization of Capital., 1902; 22 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: The Illinois Coal Operators Association, 1902. 51pp.
  - Labor and the War., 1918; 23 (Reel 54)
    New York: Allied Printing, 1918. [16 pp]
  - McNeill, George. The Eight Hour Primer., 1889; 24 (Reel 54)
    Washington: Allied Printing, 1889. 19pp.
  - Mitchell, John. The Coal Strike., 25 (Reel 54)
    No place, publisher, or date. 6pp.
  - Minutes of the Joint Conference of Anthracite Mine Operators and Correspondence Connected Therewith., 1906; 26 (Reel 54)
    New York: C.G. Burgoyne, 1906. 173pp.
  - Negotiations of Anthracite Coal Operators and Anthracite Mine Workers: Addresses of John P. White, International President, and William Green, International Statistician., 1912; 27 (Reel 54)
    Indianapolis: Cheltenham-Aetna Press, 1912. 69pp.
  - The Next Great Step for Labor., 28 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: Hollister Bros. Press, no date. 32pp.
  - Official Report of Proceedings of the Joint Conference of Miners and Operators., 1898; 29 (Reel 54)
    Columbus, Ohio: Lawrence Press Co., [1898]. 35pp.
  - Organization of the Association of Commissioners and Secretaries., 1905; 30 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: no publisher, 1905. 16pp.
  - Plain Facts About the Conditions in the Coal Mining Industry., 31 (Reel 54)
    No place, publisher, or date. 43pp
  - Platform and Constitution of the National Party. Chicago:, 32 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: New York: no publisher, no date. 19pp.
  - Proceedings of Joint Convention and Constitutional Laws of the National Progressive Union of Miners and Mine Laborers., 1888; 33 (Reel 54)
    Columbus: no publisher, 1888. 32pp.
  - Proceedings of the Joint Convention of Miners and Operators., 1906; 34 (Reel 54)
    Charleston: no publisher, 1906. 342pp.
  - Proceedings of the Third Annual Convention of the National Federation of Miners and Mine Laborers of the United States of Territories., 1887; 35 (Reel 54)
    Columbus: Myers Brothers, 1887. 16pp.
  - Program for Constructive Democracy: Message and War Program of the National Party: An Appeal to the Heart and Brain of America., 1918; 36 (Reel 54)
    Chicago: no publisher, [1918]. 19pp
  - Roberts, Peter. "The Anthracite Conflict.", 1902; 37 (Reel 54)
    Reprint. Yale Review, Nov. 1902. 11pp
  - Second Annual Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, and Pennsylvania., 1899; 38 (Reel 54)
    Pittsburgh: The Myers and Shinkle Co., 1899. 68pp.
  - Seventh Annual Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Western Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana, and Illinois., 1904; 39 (Reel 54)
    Indianapolis: C.L. Scroggs Co., 1904. 254pp.
  - Speech Delivered By John Mitchell in Support of the Report of the Committee on Boycotts., 40 (Reel 54)
    Toronto: Am. Federation of Labor, no date. 7pp.
  - Speech of William B. Wilson on Mitchell Day., 1901; 41 (Reel 54)
    Indianapolis: no publisher, 1901. 20pp
  - Strikes are War! War is Hell!! N, 42 (Reel 54)
    New York: Charles Francis Press, no date. 23pp.
  - Third Annual Joint Conference of Coal Miners and Operators of Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, and Pennsylvania., 1900; 43 (Reel 54)
    Indianapolis: no publisher, 1900. 158pp.
  - Topical Plan of Inquiry on Conditions of Labor and Capital Employed in the Mining Industry., 44 (Reel 54)
    No place, publisher or date. 9pp.
  - True Friend of the Workingman: M.A. Hanna's Record., 45 (Reel 54)
    Akron: Allied Printing, no date. 15pp.
- Photographs (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell, 1 (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell, 2 (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell, 3 (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell, 4 (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell (left), John Fallou ( right), 5 (Reel 55)
  - John Mitchell, 1905; 6 (Reel 55)
    Mt. Carmel, Pennsylvania, September 8, 1905
  - John Mitchell., 1902; 7 (Reel 55)
    Scranton, Pennsylvania, 1902
  - John Mitchell's sons: left to right: Robert, James, Richard., 1908; 8 (Reel 55)
    Spring Valley, Illinois, 1908
  - Rufus M. Barnes, 9 (Reel 55)
  - Beech Flats Coal Company. Coal Shute, 10 (Reel 55)
  - Beech Flats Coal Company. Steam Shovel, 11 (Reel 55)
  - Beech Flats Coal Company. Shunting of coal cars, 12 (Reel 55)
  - Beech Flats Coal Company. Steam shovel strip mining, 13 (Reel 55)
  - Joseph Brustead. West Bay City, Michigan, 14 (Reel 55)
  - Standing, left to right: Thomas Cairns, James Kennedy; Sitting, left to right: Henry Bausfield, Benjamin Davis, John H. Walker, 15 (Reel 55)
  - Canadian Pacific Railway station., 1901; 16 (Reel 55)
    Moose Jaw, Saskatchewan, August, 1901
  - Coal Breaker, 17 (Reel 55)
  - Clarence S. Darrow, 18 (Reel 55)
  - W.H. Deltrey, 19 (Reel 55)
  - Charles Duncan, 20 (Reel 55)
  - The "Edward F." Shaft, dumps and mill., 1905; 21 (Reel 55)
    Hassel, Montana
  - Chris Evans, 22 (Reel 55)
  - W.R. Fairley, 23 (Reel 55)
  - W.R. Fairley, 24 (Reel 55)
  - Joseph Gilneartain, 25 (Reel 55)
  - Herman Justi, 1906; 26 (Reel 55)
    Commissioner, Illinois Coal Operators' Association
  - Kehota Mining Company. Steam shovel strip mining, 1916; 27 (Reel 55)
    Redfield, Ohio, November 1916
  - Kehota Mining Company. Steam shovel, 1916; 28 (Reel 55)
  - Kehota Mining Company. Steam shovel, 1916; 29 (Reel 55)
  - Kehota Mining Company. Steam shovel, 1916; 30 (Reel 55)
  - Kehota Mining Company. Coal Shute, 1916; 31 (Reel 55)
  - Kehota Mining Company. Coal Shute., 1916; 32 (Reel 55)
  - Edward A. Kirshfield, 33 (Reel 55)
  - Capt. J.J. Kittinger, USMC., 1919; 34 (Reel 55)
    Washington, DC, June 1, 1919
  - T.L. Lewis, 1900; 35 (Reel 55)
    Bridgeport, Ohio, November 17, 1900
  - William Little, 36 (Reel 55)
  - Peter McCall, 37 (Reel 55)
  - W.N. Naskinz, 38 (Reel 55)
  - W.B. Nelson, 39 (Reel 55)
  - New Orleans, Louisiana, Jackson Park, 40 (Reel 55)
  - New York State Food Commission, 1918; 41 (Reel 55)
  - Thomas C. Parker, 42 (Reel 55)
  - D.D. Price, 43 (Reel 55)
  - Reading, Pennsylvania. Downtown, 1905; 44 (Reel 55)
    Penn St. looking east toward Mt. Penn from Fifth St.
  - Roosevelt Day at Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania., 1905; 45 (Reel 55)
    August 10, 1905.
  - Roosevelt Day at Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania. President Theodore Roosevelt addressing crowd, 1905; 46 (Reel 55)